<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windows on Blog</title>
    <link>https://valh.io/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windows on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:22:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://valh.io/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fix silently failing Docker Desktop upgrade (Windows)</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/fix-silently-failing-docker-desktop-upgrade-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/fix-silently-failing-docker-desktop-upgrade-windows/</guid>
      <description>Docker Desktop has an internal update mechanism which will, as soon as an update is available, begin asking you to apply it on every start. Unfortunately this update mechanism is not working properly for me and other users. Once you allow Docker Desktop to run the update with admin privileges nothing seems to happen and Docker also doesn&amp;rsquo;t start properly until you restart it manually.
The cause seems to be some kind of privilege problem with the Docker service running in the background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync system time automatically at Windows startup</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/sync-system-time-automatically-at-windows-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 17:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/sync-system-time-automatically-at-windows-startup/</guid>
      <description>Unlike most other operating systems, Windows 10 doesn&amp;rsquo;t sync the time with an internet service at startup by default. This can become an issue, if your mainboard&amp;rsquo;s built-in clock provides a wrong time or uses a different time zone.
If the mainboard&amp;rsquo;s battery responsible for storing time dies, it can become an even more annoying problem, because Windows will always start with an ever-growing time skew, which can eventually result in web browsing become a problem due to Windows considering websites&#39; SSL certificates not yet valid - effectively rendering browsing the majority of web pages impossible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating CPU load on Windows</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/generating-cpu-load-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 17:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/generating-cpu-load-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to check, if there was a problem with my CPU under heavy load, when running on Windows. For such purposes CPUSTRES.exe from the Sysinternals suite is very helpful.
CPUSTRES is a handy little tool to check your process for faults on heavy load. It comes with a simple GUI and allows you to instantly put heavy CPU load on your system.
CPUSTRES comes as a simple standalone program with a GUI and 4 threads to activate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
