<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog</title>
    <link>https://valh.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:22:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://valh.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fix silently failing Docker Desktop upgrade (Windows)</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/fix-silently-failing-docker-desktop-upgrade-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/fix-silently-failing-docker-desktop-upgrade-windows/</guid>
      <description>Docker Desktop has an internal update mechanism which will, as soon as an update is available, begin asking you to apply it on every start. Unfortunately this update mechanism is not working properly for me and other users. Once you allow Docker Desktop to run the update with admin privileges nothing seems to happen and Docker also doesn&amp;rsquo;t start properly until you restart it manually.
The cause seems to be some kind of privilege problem with the Docker service running in the background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sync system time automatically at Windows startup</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/sync-system-time-automatically-at-windows-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 17:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/sync-system-time-automatically-at-windows-startup/</guid>
      <description>Unlike most other operating systems, Windows 10 doesn&amp;rsquo;t sync the time with an internet service at startup by default. This can become an issue, if your mainboard&amp;rsquo;s built-in clock provides a wrong time or uses a different time zone.
If the mainboard&amp;rsquo;s battery responsible for storing time dies, it can become an even more annoying problem, because Windows will always start with an ever-growing time skew, which can eventually result in web browsing become a problem due to Windows considering websites&amp;rsquo; SSL certificates not yet valid - effectively rendering browsing the majority of web pages impossible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let HomeAssistant notify you of updates</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/let-homeassistant-notify-you-of-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 19:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/let-homeassistant-notify-you-of-updates/</guid>
      <description>HomeAssistant releases new updates very regularly. Each month there is a new release which usually receives several patch releases as well. If you want to keep up with updates or even update automatically, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to get notified upon the release of an update.
Prerequisites HomeAssistant has a built-in updater sensor which automatically checks for the updates and changes state, if it finds one. This can be used as trigger in an automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python cheat sheet for InfluxDB2 (influxdb_client)</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/python-cheat-sheet-for-influxdb2-influxdb_client/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 15:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/python-cheat-sheet-for-influxdb2-influxdb_client/</guid>
      <description>Setup InfluxDB test instance with Docker docker run -d -p 8086:8086 --name influxdb influxdb This command pulls the latest InfluxDB image from Docker Hub, runs it with the name influxdb and makes the default port 8086 available on localhost. Once the container is up and running, we need to setup InfluxDB before we can use it.
Open a shell in the InfluxDB container:
docker exec -it influxdb bash Start the interactive setup wizard by running influx setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk: How SUSE migrated 200k user accounts to UCS</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/talk-how-suse-migrated-200k-user-accounts-to-ucs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 17:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/talk-how-suse-migrated-200k-user-accounts-to-ucs/</guid>
      <description>During my time as a Consultant &amp;amp; Engineer with Univention, I supported Daniel Schmidt and his colleagues at SUSE in their migration of 200k user accounts from a legacy identity management to Univention Corporate Server (UCS).
It was a live migration over the course of weekend and I provided technical consulting as well as live patches and enhancements to UCS for issues and areas of improvements which were found during the migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python script for Cloudflare DNS record updates (DynDNS)</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/python-script-for-cloudflare-dns-record-updates-dyndns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 15:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/python-script-for-cloudflare-dns-record-updates-dyndns/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is an update to a post from 2019 and features a rewrite in Python with various new features including IPv6 support, logging, argument parser, &amp;hellip;
Why I&amp;rsquo;m using Cloudflare as CDN and DNS provider as well as domain registrar. For a system with an external IPv4 address that changes daily I needed a way to dynamically update a DNS record at Cloudflare with the system&amp;rsquo;s current external IP address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple CLI audio metadata editor: tag_dat.py</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/simple-cli-audio-metadata-editor-tag_dat.py/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 17:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/simple-cli-audio-metadata-editor-tag_dat.py/</guid>
      <description>Audio metadata is often not particularly easy to manage in a simple and quick manner. There&amp;rsquo;s lots of tools providing this feature but many of them have a ton of other additional functionality or are full-on music library managers. I wanted a very simple command-line tool to quickly change the title, artist and album tags of audio metadata - the result is &amp;ldquo;tag_dat.py&amp;rdquo; and available in my tools repository.
tag_dat.py iterates over a file or all files in a given path (default: current path), sets the filename (without file ending) as title and given arguments album and artist as audio tags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Ledger Live working on NixOS</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/get-ledger-live-working-on-nixos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 18:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/get-ledger-live-working-on-nixos/</guid>
      <description>The Ledger Nano series are hardware wallets for crypto currencies. They&amp;rsquo;re managed through an application called Ledger Live. Ledger Live runs on linux but might - depending on your distro - require some adjustments in order to correctly identify the device via USB. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t test whether this config works with all Ledger devices so far. Feel free to drop me a tweet if you have anything to add to this post and I&amp;rsquo;ll gladly update it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Providing access to thousands of external storages using Nextcloud</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/providing-access-to-thousands-of-external-storages-using-nextcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 18:41:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/providing-access-to-thousands-of-external-storages-using-nextcloud/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I&amp;rsquo;ve held a talk involving a solution I&amp;rsquo;ve built @univention for a customer using Univention Corporate Server and Nextcloud at this year&amp;rsquo;s Nextcloud conference.
The talk is available on YouTube.
The documentation for the cool solution I&amp;rsquo;m referring to in the talk can be found in the Univention Knowledge Base.
Thanks a lot to the folks at Nextcloud and especially Nina and Jos for the invitation and great discussions!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextcloud for UCS now comes with SSO out of the box</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/nextcloud-for-ucs-now-comes-with-sso-out-of-the-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 13:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/nextcloud-for-ucs-now-comes-with-sso-out-of-the-box/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I&amp;rsquo;ve held a talk involving a solution I built @univention for a customer using Univention Corporate Server and Nextcloud at this year&amp;rsquo;s Nextcloud conference. The video of that will probably be available in the next few weeks and I&amp;rsquo;ll share it here once it&amp;rsquo;s available.
UPDATE: See here for the video of the talk.
Another interesting thing regarding Nextcloud and UCS happened in the meantime though: The Nextcloud app for UCS now comes with pre-configured Single Sign-On (SSO) using SAML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi: Configure WLAN/WiFi &#43; SSH before first boot</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/raspberry-pi-configure-wlan/wifi--ssh-before-first-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 19:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/raspberry-pi-configure-wlan/wifi--ssh-before-first-boot/</guid>
      <description>Why Lots of Raspberry Pis are used for purposes requiring a wireless network connection. Configuring WLAN for the Pi requires a config file including the network&amp;rsquo;s name and access keys. To save time otherwise spent on connecting the Pi to a screen and keyboard or wired network to configure this, you can just create the config file before even booting the Pi for the first time. Here&amp;rsquo;s how that works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple file encryption module for Python projects</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/simple-file-encryption-module-for-python-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 11:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/simple-file-encryption-module-for-python-projects/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Plasm focuses on a very specific use case: encrypting and decrypting files using public key encryption. If plasm doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit the scope of what you want to do, feel free to have a look at pynacl&amp;rsquo;s documentation and use it directly.
Why I have experimented a lot with camera software for the Raspberry Pi. One project that particularly stuck with me is motionEye, a web frontend for the motion daemon, which allows you to easily set up an open source motion triggered camera for about 50€.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up unattended upgrades on Debian</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/setting-up-unattended-upgrades-on-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 12:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/setting-up-unattended-upgrades-on-debian/</guid>
      <description>Why I have a Raspberry Pi running on Raspbian in my home network. It mainly provides a DNS server based on Pi Hole and runs some cronjobs for me. Of course you don&amp;rsquo;t want to login to such a system regularly and install package upgrades. That&amp;rsquo;s where unattended upgrades come into play. I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how to set unattended upgrades up on Debian and walk you through some config parameters that I find very useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Userscript to hide YouTube comments</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/userscript-to-hide-youtube-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/userscript-to-hide-youtube-comments/</guid>
      <description>Why Most comments below YouTube videos are, well, irrelevant, to say the least. Since they&amp;rsquo;re pretty much in the middle of the page, they still regularly caught my eyes and distracted me when I was checking the recommended videos and scrolled down the site. That&amp;rsquo;s why I built a little userscript to hide the comments by default and make them visible with the click of a button.
Installing the script Chrome Just download the script by right-clicking and selecting Save link as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to play YouTube in background on mobile</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/how-to-play-youtube-in-background-on-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/how-to-play-youtube-in-background-on-mobile/</guid>
      <description>One of the most requested features for mobile devices in, well, forever, is playing YouTube videos without having the app in foreground. YouTube introduced this feature with YouTube Red for paying customers. So if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to live in one of the countries, where you can actually subscribe to YouTube Red, you can pay a few bucks per month to get this.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not so lucky (like me) or just don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay, you could still use a mobile browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix NoScript 10 (Quantum) default settings</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/fix-noscript-10-quantum-default-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/fix-noscript-10-quantum-default-settings/</guid>
      <description>The release of Firefox 57 was a major disruptive event in the Mozilla community. One of the major changes was the migration of add-ons away from XUL/XPCOM to WebExtensions. While this change makes it easier for developers to integrate their existing (Chrome) add-ons with Firefox, it also forced Firefox add-on developers to rewrite their entire add-ons from scratch. Some devs (like the very popular DownThemAll) were very frustrated and abandoned decades of code and tens of thousands of users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating CPU load on Windows</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/generating-cpu-load-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 17:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/generating-cpu-load-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to check, if there was a problem with my CPU under heavy load, when running on Windows. For such purposes CPUSTRES.exe from the Sysinternals suite is very helpful.
CPUSTRES is a handy little tool to check your process for faults on heavy load. It comes with a simple GUI and allows you to instantly put heavy CPU load on your system.
CPUSTRES comes as a simple standalone program with a GUI and 4 threads to activate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post</title>
      <link>https://valh.io/p/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 13:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://valh.io/p/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a test Welcome!
2nd level headline 3rd level headline </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
