<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technology on Blog</title><link>https://valh.io/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in Technology on Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 18:24:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://valh.io/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Android TV Cheat Sheet</title><link>https://valh.io/p/android-tv-cheat-sheet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 18:24:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/android-tv-cheat-sheet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I ventured further into the world of Android TV using Android 11 on a &lt;a href="https://www.mi.com/global/product/xiaomi-tv-stick-4k/">Xiaomi TV Stick 4K&lt;/a>. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll share some insights to get the most out of your Android TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keep in mind that not all of these might work the same way or at all on any Android TV device! Most of them should, though. When in doubt, try and search for your device&amp;rsquo;s name and what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi: Configure WLAN/WiFi + SSH before first boot</title><link>https://valh.io/p/raspberry-pi-configure-wlan/wifi--ssh-before-first-boot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 14:03:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/raspberry-pi-configure-wlan/wifi--ssh-before-first-boot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lots of Raspberry Pis are used for purposes that require a wireless network connection and remote access. To save time otherwise spent on connecting the Pi to a screen and keyboard or wired network to configure this, you can just configure network, SSH and an initial user before the first boot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post documents an interactive and a non-interactive approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="interactively-with-raspberry-pi-imager">Interactively with Raspberry Pi Imager&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The Raspberry Pi Foundation provides an imaging tool, allowing you to not only flash the current Raspberry Pi OS to a given device but also to configure a few things in the same step.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Windows Auto Dark Mode - Change multi-screen wallpaper</title><link>https://valh.io/p/windows-auto-dark-mode-change-multi-screen-wallpaper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:43:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/windows-auto-dark-mode-change-multi-screen-wallpaper/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-tool">The tool&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>AutoDarkMode&lt;/strong> is a great open source tool to automatically switch between dark and light themes on Windows. You can set custom hours, switch manually or use sunset and sunrise from your location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can download it and contribute &lt;a href="https://github.com/AutoDarkMode/Windows-Auto-Night-Mode">here on GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can also change your wallpaper to a light or dark one - &lt;em>but only on one screen&lt;/em>. Since I have a dual screen setup and a soft spot for ultra-wide wallpapers, there had to be a way!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Workaround for broken DNS in WSL2</title><link>https://valh.io/p/workaround-for-broken-dns-in-wsl2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 12:34:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/workaround-for-broken-dns-in-wsl2/</guid><description>&lt;p>WSL2 uses the Windows host&amp;rsquo;s DNS - so if DNS is working on Windows, normally WSL2 should be fine as well! Unfortunately, DNS in WSL2 just randomly stopped working for me at some point. The &lt;code>/etc/resolv.conf&lt;/code> file generated by WSL2 was still being correctly created but DNS just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily there are plenty of ways to work around this, because we can just do DNS ourselves inside the Linux running in WSL2.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fix silently failing Docker Desktop upgrade (Windows)</title><link>https://valh.io/p/fix-silently-failing-docker-desktop-upgrade-windows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 12:22:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/fix-silently-failing-docker-desktop-upgrade-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>Docker Desktop has an internal update mechanism which will, as soon as an update is available, begin asking you to apply it on every start. Unfortunately this update mechanism is not working properly for me and other users. Once you allow Docker Desktop to run the update with admin privileges nothing seems to happen and Docker also doesn&amp;rsquo;t start properly until you restart it manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cause seems to be some kind of privilege problem with the Docker service running in the background. Here is a workaround that works nicely for me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sync system time automatically at Windows startup</title><link>https://valh.io/p/sync-system-time-automatically-at-windows-startup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 17:22:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/sync-system-time-automatically-at-windows-startup/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>: The Windows time sync service is not working reliably. It was working fine on my system for a few months but stopped syncing time properly eventually even though it is still being started automatically. Feel free to give it a try nonetheless but know that this seems to be another one of Windows&amp;rsquo; great unreliable mysteries&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike most other operating systems, Windows 10 doesn&amp;rsquo;t sync the time with an internet service at startup by default. This can become an issue, if your mainboard&amp;rsquo;s built-in clock provides a wrong time or uses a different time zone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let HomeAssistant notify you of updates</title><link>https://valh.io/p/let-homeassistant-notify-you-of-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 19:21:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/let-homeassistant-notify-you-of-updates/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.home-assistant.io/">HomeAssistant&lt;/a> releases new updates very regularly. Each month there is a new release which usually receives several patch releases as well. If you want to keep up with updates or even update automatically, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to get notified upon the release of an update.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>HomeAssistant has a built-in updater sensor which automatically checks for the updates and changes state, if it finds one. This can be used as &lt;code>trigger&lt;/code> in an automation. The automation&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>action&lt;/code> can do all kinds of things; e.g. send a notification to a phone, which has the HomeAssistant app installed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Python cheat sheet for InfluxDB2 (influxdb_client)</title><link>https://valh.io/p/python-cheat-sheet-for-influxdb2-influxdb_client/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 15:53:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/python-cheat-sheet-for-influxdb2-influxdb_client/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="setup-influxdb-test-instance-with-docker">Setup InfluxDB test instance with Docker&lt;/h1>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">docker run -d -p 8086:8086 --name influxdb influxdb
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This command pulls the latest InfluxDB image from Docker Hub, runs it with the name &lt;code>influxdb&lt;/code> and makes the default port &lt;code>8086&lt;/code> available on &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code>.
Once the container is up and running, we need to setup InfluxDB before we can use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open a shell in the InfluxDB container:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">docker &lt;span class="nb">exec&lt;/span> -it influxdb bash
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Start the interactive setup wizard by running &lt;code>influx setup&lt;/code>.
The wizard will ask you to provide initial admin credentials, your first organization, your first bucket and a retention period for it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Talk: How SUSE migrated 200k user accounts to UCS</title><link>https://valh.io/p/talk-how-suse-migrated-200k-user-accounts-to-ucs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 17:50:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/talk-how-suse-migrated-200k-user-accounts-to-ucs/</guid><description>&lt;p>During my time as a Consultant &amp;amp; Engineer with &lt;a href="https://univention.com">Univention&lt;/a>, I supported Daniel Schmidt and his colleagues at &lt;a href="https://suse.com">SUSE&lt;/a> in their migration of 200k user accounts from a legacy identity management to &lt;a href="https://univention.com">Univention Corporate Server&lt;/a> (UCS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was a live migration over the course of weekend and I provided technical consulting as well as live patches and enhancements to UCS for issues and areas of improvements which were found during the migration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During this year&amp;rsquo;s virtual Univention Summit, Daniel presented that story in a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q-NY9JCz6VA">talk&lt;/a> which I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you. The talk is in German and - at this point - has no English subtitles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Python script for Cloudflare DNS record updates (DynDNS)</title><link>https://valh.io/p/python-script-for-cloudflare-dns-record-updates-dyndns/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 15:53:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/python-script-for-cloudflare-dns-record-updates-dyndns/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong> This is an update to a post from 2019 and features a rewrite in Python with various new features including IPv6 support, logging, argument parser, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="why">Why&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m using Cloudflare as CDN and DNS provider as well as domain registrar. For a system with an external IPv4 address that changes daily I needed a way to dynamically update a DNS record at Cloudflare with the system&amp;rsquo;s current external IP address.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple CLI audio metadata editor: tag_dat.py</title><link>https://valh.io/p/simple-cli-audio-metadata-editor-tag_dat.py/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 17:11:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/simple-cli-audio-metadata-editor-tag_dat.py/</guid><description>&lt;p>Audio metadata is often not particularly easy to manage in a simple and quick manner. There&amp;rsquo;s lots of tools providing this feature but many of them have a ton of other additional functionality or are full-on music library managers. I wanted a very simple command-line tool to quickly change the title, artist and album tags of audio metadata - the result is &amp;ldquo;tag_dat.py&amp;rdquo; and available in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/va1entin/tools/tree/master/tag_dat">tools repository&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>tag_dat.py iterates over a file or all files in a given path (default: current path), sets the filename (without file ending) as &lt;em>title&lt;/em> and given arguments &lt;em>album&lt;/em> and &lt;em>artist&lt;/em> as audio tags. The script uses the amazing &amp;ldquo;mutagen&amp;rdquo; library under the hood.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Get Ledger Live working on NixOS</title><link>https://valh.io/p/get-ledger-live-working-on-nixos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 18:21:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/get-ledger-live-working-on-nixos/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://ledger.com">Ledger Nano series&lt;/a> are hardware wallets for crypto currencies. They&amp;rsquo;re managed through an application called &lt;a href="https://shop.ledger.com/pages/ledger-live">Ledger Live&lt;/a>. Ledger Live runs on linux but might - depending on your distro - require some adjustments in order to correctly identify the device via USB.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t test whether this config works with all Ledger devices so far. Feel free to drop me a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/valhei">tweet&lt;/a> if you have anything to add to this post and I&amp;rsquo;ll gladly update it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Providing access to thousands of external storages using Nextcloud</title><link>https://valh.io/p/providing-access-to-thousands-of-external-storages-using-nextcloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 18:41:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/providing-access-to-thousands-of-external-storages-using-nextcloud/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few weeks ago I&amp;rsquo;ve held a talk involving a solution I&amp;rsquo;ve built @&lt;a href="https://univention.com">univention&lt;/a> for a customer using Univention Corporate Server and Nextcloud at this year&amp;rsquo;s Nextcloud conference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The talk is available &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZjLiSL_XYvs&amp;amp;t=1766">on YouTube&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The documentation for the cool solution I&amp;rsquo;m referring to in the talk can be found in the &lt;a href="https://help.univention.com/t/cool-solution-mount-samba-shares-in-nextcloud/">Univention Knowledge Base&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks a lot to the folks at Nextcloud and especially &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nlapalice">Nina&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jospoortvliet">Jos&lt;/a> for the invitation and great discussions!&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZjLiSL_XYvs?start=1766" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>Nextcloud for UCS now comes with SSO out of the box</title><link>https://valh.io/p/nextcloud-for-ucs-now-comes-with-sso-out-of-the-box/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 13:42:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/nextcloud-for-ucs-now-comes-with-sso-out-of-the-box/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few weeks ago I&amp;rsquo;ve held a talk involving a solution I built @&lt;a href="https://univention.com">univention&lt;/a> for a customer using Univention Corporate Server and Nextcloud at this year&amp;rsquo;s Nextcloud conference. The video of that will probably be available in the next few weeks and I&amp;rsquo;ll share it here once it&amp;rsquo;s available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UPDATE: See &lt;a href="https://valh.io/blog/Nextcloud-conference-2019.html">here&lt;/a> for the video of the talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another interesting thing regarding Nextcloud and UCS happened in the meantime though: The &lt;a href="https://www.univention.com/products/univention-app-center/app-catalog/nextcloud/">Nextcloud app for UCS&lt;/a> now comes with pre-configured Single Sign-On (SSO) using SAML. This is very cool because lots of our customers want to make use of SSO but the configuration is not always trivial. Using a &lt;a href="https://www.univention.com/blog-en/2019/02/how-to-single-sign-on-for-nextcloud/">blog post&lt;/a> I wrote for the Univention blog in February, Nextcloud, namely Arthur Schiwon aka @&lt;a href="https://github.com/blizzz">blizzz&lt;/a>, were able to &lt;a href="https://github.com/nextcloud/univention-app/issues/91">bake the configuration&lt;/a> into the app and thus make it really easy for people to get started with UCS, Nextcloud and SSO! If you&amp;rsquo;d like to find out more about SSO with SAML, feel free to check out my &lt;a href="https://www.univention.com/blog-en/2019/06/brief-introduction-saml-a-secure-comfortable-web-access/">blog post&lt;/a> about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple file encryption module for Python projects</title><link>https://valh.io/p/simple-file-encryption-module-for-python-projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 11:40:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/simple-file-encryption-module-for-python-projects/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="tldr">tl;dr&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Plasm focuses on a very specific use case: encrypting and decrypting files using public key encryption. If plasm doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit the scope of what you want to do, feel free to have a look at &lt;a href="https://pynacl.readthedocs.io">pynacl&amp;rsquo;s documentation&lt;/a> and use it directly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="why">Why&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I have experimented a lot with camera software for the Raspberry Pi. One project that particularly stuck with me is &lt;a href="https://github.com/ccrisan/motioneye">motionEye&lt;/a>, a web frontend for the motion daemon, which allows you to easily set up an open source motion triggered camera for about 50€.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting up unattended upgrades on Debian</title><link>https://valh.io/p/setting-up-unattended-upgrades-on-debian/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 12:30:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/setting-up-unattended-upgrades-on-debian/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="why">Why&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I have a Raspberry Pi running on Raspbian in my home network. It mainly provides a DNS server based on &lt;a href="https://pi-hole.net/">Pi Hole&lt;/a> and runs some cronjobs for me.
Of course you don&amp;rsquo;t want to login to such a system regularly and install package upgrades. That&amp;rsquo;s where unattended upgrades come into play.
I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you how to set unattended upgrades up on Debian and walk you through some config parameters that I find very useful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Userscript to hide YouTube comments</title><link>https://valh.io/p/userscript-to-hide-youtube-comments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/userscript-to-hide-youtube-comments/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="why">Why&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Most comments below YouTube videos are, well, irrelevant, to say the least.
Since they&amp;rsquo;re pretty much in the middle of the page, they still regularly caught my eyes and distracted me when I was checking the recommended videos and scrolled down the site.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I built a little userscript to hide the comments by default and make them visible with the click of a button.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="installing-the-script">Installing the script&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="chrome">Chrome&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Just &lt;a href="https://github.com/va1entin/configs/raw/master/userscripts/hide-yt-comments.user.js">download the script&lt;/a> by right-clicking and selecting &lt;em>Save link as&lt;/em>. Open &lt;code>chrome://extensions&lt;/code> and drag-and-drop the file into Chrome. Chrome should ask, if you want to install it. You can also disable or remove it here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to play YouTube in background on mobile</title><link>https://valh.io/p/how-to-play-youtube-in-background-on-mobile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 21:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/how-to-play-youtube-in-background-on-mobile/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most requested features for mobile devices in, well, forever, is playing YouTube videos without having the app in foreground. YouTube introduced this feature with YouTube Red for paying customers. So if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough to live in one of the countries, where you can actually subscribe to YouTube Red, you can pay a few bucks per month to get this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re not so lucky (like me) or just don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay, you could still use a mobile browser. Until recently at least, when YouTube blocked playing videos without having the according tab open on mobile devices. This is accomplished by utilizing the so called page visibility and fullscreen API. This allows a webpage to check, if you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> viewing the page.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fix NoScript 10 (Quantum) default settings</title><link>https://valh.io/p/fix-noscript-10-quantum-default-settings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/fix-noscript-10-quantum-default-settings/</guid><description>&lt;p>The release of Firefox 57 was a major disruptive event in the Mozilla community. One of the major changes was the migration of add-ons away from XUL/XPCOM to WebExtensions. While this change makes it easier for developers to integrate their existing (Chrome) add-ons with Firefox, it also forced Firefox add-on developers to rewrite their entire add-ons from scratch. Some devs (like the very popular DownThemAll) were &lt;a href="https://www.downthemall.net/re-downthemall-and-webextensions-or-why-why-i-am-done-with-mozilla/">very frustrated&lt;/a> and abandoned decades of code and tens of thousands of users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generating CPU load on Windows</title><link>https://valh.io/p/generating-cpu-load-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 17:27:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valh.io/p/generating-cpu-load-on-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently wanted to check, if there was a problem with my CPU under heavy load, when running on Windows. For such purposes &lt;a href="http://download.sysinternals.com/files/CPUSTRES.zip">CPUSTRES.exe from the Sysinternals suite&lt;/a> is very helpful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CPUSTRES is a handy little tool to check your process for faults on heavy load.
It comes with a simple GUI and allows you to instantly put heavy CPU load on your system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CPUSTRES comes as a simple standalone program with a GUI and 4 threads to activate. You can also assign different intesities per thread. Task manager helps checking how much load is actually put on the CPU.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>